[
    {
        "question": "Dampness in the air",
        "options": [
            "Moisture (humidity)",
            "Evaporation",
            "Saturation"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of water vapour in 1 cu.m of air is the …………… of the air.",
        "options": [
            "Relative humidity",
            "Absolute humidity",
            "Negligible humidity"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Clouds are found at different …………… above mean seal level.",
        "options": [
            "Longitude",
            "Latitude",
            "Altitude"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The humidity in the air mainly depends on the ……………",
        "options": [
            "Temperature",
            "Weather",
            "Rain",
            "Temperature"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Dark clouds in the sky is the sign of a ……………",
        "options": [
            "Rainy day",
            "Sunny day",
            "Cold day"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In the afternoon the temperature increases, relative humidity ……………",
        "options": [
            "Decreases",
            "Increases",
            "Remains same"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Cirrus, Cirro-cumulus and Cirro-Stratus are mostly form between ……………",
        "options": [
            "7000 m to 14000 m",
            "2000 m to 700 m",
            "Less than 2000 m"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The amount of water vapour in 1 cu.m. of air is the …………… humidity of the air.",
        "options": [
            "Relative",
            "Absolute",
            "Water holding"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The climate of Rajasthan is hot and dry because of ……………",
        "options": [
            "More moisture",
            "Less rain",
            "No moisture"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Relative humidity mean when water vapour in the air reached to the …………… point.",
        "options": [
            "Dew",
            "Fog",
            "Saturated"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Moisture in the air is ……………",
        "options": [
            "Visible",
            "Invisible",
            "Present"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Dew, frost and fog are the forms of condensation at the ……………",
        "options": [
            "Higher elevato",
            "Ground level",
            "Vertical level"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Find particles of ice and water accumulate around …………… particles in the air.",
        "options": [
            "Soil",
            "Dust",
            "Moisture"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "…………… air can hold more moistures in the air.",
        "options": [
            "Cool",
            "Moist",
            "Warmer"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": " When the temperature of the air is 35 C, its vapour holding capacity is 33.37 sm/cu.m.  If the absolute humidity is 20 gm/cu.m the what would be the relative humidity",
        "options": [
            "59.93%",
            "59.25%",
            "59.40%"
        ],
        "answer": 1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Indicator of pleasant weather.",
        "options": [
            "Cumulonimbus clouds",
            "Cumulus clouds",
            "Cirrus clouds"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The process of cloud framing : Evaporation, vertical current, saturation ……………",
        "options": [
            "Dew point",
            "Higher elevation",
            "Condensation"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "When the temperature is low and the relative humidity is high ……………",
        "options": [
            "Process of evaporation begins",
            "Vapour holding capacity is more",
            "Process of condensation begins."
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Cumulonimbus clouds accompanied by ……………",
        "options": [
            "Lightening",
            "Heavy rain",
            "Storm"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Put the process in order : Vertical current, precipitation, cloud formation condensation, Evaporation",
        "options": [
            "Condensation, vertical current, cloud formation, evaporation precipitation",
            "Evaporation, vertical current, cloud formation, precipitation condensation",
            "Evaporation, vertical current condensation, cloud formation, precipitation."
        ],
        "answer": 3
    }
]